NICK MEINCKEN

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Surbiton, Surrey UK
+44 7967 961441
nick@meincken.com

I am an experienced AEM Front End Developer. I specialise in creating clean semantic code to ensure fast load times. I follow atomic design principles where possible and develop style guides to ensure consistent and rapid development when working as part of a team. I am as comfortable coding in raw HTML as Lam using products such as React

I enjoy working as part of an Agile team and have worked on some of the countries largest e-commerce sites.

Languages

Semantic HTML - 20 years

CSS - 20 years

Vanilla JS/jQuery - 15 years

SCSS - 8 years

PostCSS - 3 years

Framework/Libraries

React - 3 years

Gatsby - 2 years

Tools

Photoshop CC - 20 years

Atom - 4 years

Sketch/Zeplin - 4 years

VS Code - 1 years

Platforms

Bundlers - 5 years

Bundlers: Webpack, Grunt, Gulp, Parcel

CMS - 15 years

CMS's: AEM, Shopify, Wordpress, Jekyll

Qualifications

Adobe Training Center (2015)

AEM Sites developer

The Community College Hackney (2006)

BTEC Web Authoring Level II (distinction

Spelthorne College, Middlesex (1997)

BTEC Photography & Business Skills

Ashford High School (1994)

6 GCSEs including Maths, English and

Employment History

3|Share

Senior Developer February 2022 - November 2023

Support for AEM front end builds by improving page performance and optimisation of legacy code base. Working as part of a team spread across the globe to provide an excellent service to our clients.

Relevant skills: AEM DAM CSS JS

Adobe

Front End Architect August 2021 - January 2022

Building a scalable design system for migrating a large number of sites from different AEM/Wordpress environments to the newer AEMCS. Creating a robust reusable pattern library which can be branded for a specific brand with a simple to update config. Delivering the proof of concept to the client via a well documented presentations and videos.

Relevant skills: BuildScripts SCSS AEM CoreComponents Migration

Diva-E

Front End Developer June 2021 - July 2021

Providing support and minor bug fixing for AEM frontend builds.

Relevant skills: AEM (S)CSS TypeScript Kluntje

Deloitte Belgium

React UI Developer March 2021 - May 2021

Building a profile builder for an external client in NextJS with GraphQL and D3js. Adding in linting tools and styled-components to the build to improve developer workflow and also adding in prettier config to keep the development process clean and tidy. Setting up rules for the code base

Relevant skills: NextJS GraphQL prettier stylelint styled-components

We Make Websites

Full Stack Developer Nov 2020 - Jan 2021

Helping with support of client development adding new features and components to their Shopify themes and also bug fixing existing components.

Relevant skills: Shopify SCSS Liquid ¡Query JavaScript VueJS Slate Asana

Crabtree & Evelyn

Full Stack Developer Apr 2020 - Oct 2020

Full stack dev, dealing with build and deployment of new features on the Crabtree & Evelyn website. Built on Shopify and migrating to a distributed development process with Bitbucket integration to setting up deployment environments.

Relevant skills: Shopify Liquid jQuery CI/CD

Grundfos Denmark

Front End Engineer Dec 2019 - Feb 2020

Grundfos is a globally recognised company which develops water solutions around the world. Building components for AEM in standard HTM in Sightly but also utilising a custom VueJS front end design system using BEM Atomic Design principles.

Relevant skills: AEM VueJS SCSS Atomic BEM Sightly AEM_Dialog Sling node.js NPM

Texture London

Front End Developer Nov 2019 - Dec 2019

Front end developer role with minimal back end skills for Shopify. Building online shopping portal for a luxury brand.

Relevant skills: Shopify Liquid SCSS ¡Query ¡QueryUI

Signal Noise

Front End Developer Aug 2019 - Oct 2019

Building AEM components for Siemens using postcss and PatternLab. This project contained the use of Stylelint, PostCSS and BEM within Gulp. It drew in a lot of style rules from other projects created by Signal Noise for Siemens.

Relevant skills: PostCSS Stylint BEM PatternLab Handlebars React Bootstrap GIT

Pomegranate

Front End Developer Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

Building components around the bootstrap framework for a Medical website utilising Handlebars, LESS and jQuery. Sample components and page templates for a CMS. Built the base for reusable components and sections.

Relevant skills: Less Gulp Handlebars GIT Bootstrap HTML templates

ВТ

Front End Developer May 2018 - Jun 2019

BT is a globally recognized telecoms brand. I have been working as part of the Marketing, Brand and Data teams in rebuilding their email templates in AEM for integration into ACM. My main task has been migrating and updating the email templates within AEM to be responsive with more control for the user. I have also worked on a number microsites for campaigns within ACM (Adobe Campaign).

Relevant skills: AEM ACM GIT Granite UI Touch UI HTL Mustache Grunt Node SCSS VanillaJS Email Development/Styleguide Agile Workfront

GTA Travel

Front End UI Developer Jan 2018 - May 2018

GTA Travel have been powering global travel for 40 years. I came on board as part of the marketing team to work on marketing projects and general site optimisation. I am also part of a wider group that has been tasked to create new components and develop a style guide for the site.

Relevant skills: SCSS React ATG Jira GIT Sketch PhotoShop InDesign RESTful API Handlebars WebPack/Gulp

Matter of Form

Front End Developer May 2017 - Oct 2017

Working as part of a small agile development team in Old Street on a high quality, design led project updating a boutique travel website. Building on modular patterns for CSS, JS and HTML for a CMS.

Relevant skills: SCSS jQuery jQueryUI Jira GIT Sketch Handlebars WebPack Responsive component design

MerchantCantos

Front End Developer Jan 2017 - Feb 2017 & Mar 2017

Working as part of a small development team building custom websites for corporate finance using .Net and Umbraco. Support for existing websites and updating an older site to newer code

Relevant skills: SCSS jQuery Umbraco Responsive design

Rapha

Front End Developer Sep 2016 - Nov 2016

Cleaning up the code base of this prestige clothing brand and general site and performance improvements as well as building the new about pages on Wordpress and the updated Cycle Club section.

Relevant skills: SCSS ¡Query Java Hybris CMS/Wordpress Responsive design

We Are Social

Front End Developer Sep 2016 - Sep 2016

Microsite for Blind Pig Cider using Wordpress with custom fields and utilising a mobile first design principle as well as improving the mixins for SCSS.

Relevant skills: Custom Wordpress components Responsive design PHP SCSS jQuery PictureFill CSS3 HTML5

Virgin Media

Front End Developer Nov 2009 - Aug 2016

One of the UK's leading entertainment and communication providers, I was a member of a team of developers working on moving Virgin Media to a fully responsive website and migrating from multiple instances of CQ5 to a single version of AEM6. First hand experience with AEM adapting many of the core components within AEM to modified and customised versions specifically for Virgin Media, as well as custom components.

Relevant skills: Building components for AEM HTML5 jQuery CSS3 Building online styleguide Tactical and Strategic redesign HTML Agile work process Responsive and Adaptive builds